What if you had a full stack ML engineer
that never sleeps? One that can explore
data, engineer features, train models,
tune them, deploy, and even monitor them
all on its own. Well, this is where I'd
like to introduce Neo, the world's first
autonomous machine learning engineer.
And it's truly impressive. Neo is a
super intelligent AI engineer built to
handle the entire ML workflow end to end
with human in the loop control so you're
always in charge. It's powered by 11
specialized agents and a brand new
multi- aent orchestrator. Neo achieved
the highest score on open AI's MLE bench
with the 34.2 percentage. This is
surpassing Deepseek, Microsoft's RD
Agent, Aid, Open Hands, and proving
itself across 75 Kaggle competitions.
But Neo isn't just about benchmarks.
It's actually designed for realworld use
cases. Neo also has a VPC mode, so the
data never actually leaves your
environment. There's also an effort
quotient where you can choose how deeply
Neo should actually reason from quick
drafts to actual production ready
builds. So overall, this isn't just a
coding assistant. This is an ML engineer
that's faster, tireless, and built to
make every workflow 10 times faster. In
essence, Neo streamlines machine
learning end to end that is going to
take you from an idea to code to
insights in a single interface. But now
let's actually see it in action. This is
where Neo was actually asked to build a
speech recognition model for clinical
transcriptions. It actually fine-tuned
the whisper small model, successfully
reducing the word error rate, which is
pretty impressive.
In this example, when Neo was tasked
with building an ETA prediction model
from a public data set, it handled the
entire pipeline autonomously from data
cleaning and feature engineering to
model selection and hyperparameter
tuning. It evaluated the model and
generated detailed metrics and
visualizations. And finally, Neo
produced a productionready prediction
pipeline with fully documented code and
reproducible steps. This is why I really
wanted to make a video on Neo cuz it is
truly remarkable. Now, unfortunately,
it's not fully available for everyone
yet, but you can request access as they
are moving into their early access
phase. So, if you are an individual or a
company, you can simply request for NEO
by heading over to this page, which I'll
leave a link to in the description
below. But thankfully, I have gotten
access to Neo. So, this way I can
showcase all the features of part of it.
But let's say if you do get access,
you'll then be sent over to the Neo
dashboard. This is where you can manage
all of your projects or access example
projects to get a better feel of Neo.
You can also access them through the
lefth hand panel. You can manage your
secret keys. You can view the docs as
well as the settings. Now, the docs is
where you can get more details about the
VPC mode and a couple other
configuration docs. So, if you're
interested, definitely take a look at
this with the link in the description
below. Before we get started, I just
want to mention that you should
definitely go ahead and subscribe to the
World of AI newsletter. I'm constantly
posting different newsletters on a
weekly basis. So this is where you can
easily get up-to-date knowledge about
what is happening in the AI space. So
definitely go ahead and subscribe as
this is completely for free. Here is an
example where Neo is going to
autonomously build a chat moderation
pipeline and you can see how helpful Neo
actually is. In this demo, I actually
asked it to detect profanity in harmful
text in messages. And since there's no
real data set which was provided, Neo is
going to generate a synthetic data set
that covers English messages and it
includes profanity, hate speech,
bullying and explicit threats. But to
ensure the system is practical for real
world use, it was able to define key
parameters like the chat environment
should handle moderate to high message
volumes with low latency detection. And
the main success metric is high recall
for harmful content. that's balanced
with reasonable precision measured by F1
scores. And right now you can see the
first pass ledger list is the stage one
where it's focusing on the data set
engineering and the preparation. This is
where it's going to run to focus on
things like analyzing the moderation
categories, creating a comprehensive
annotation guideline and a couple other
tasks. And you can see that this is a
super agent that will autonomously
handle end-to-end pipeline tasks from
data generation all the way to
processing the model training evaluation
to deployment and all of this is
designed to integrate seamlessly with a
python-based backend and this will
provide real time moderation through an
API.
Right now it is taking off all the tasks
that it's completing like creating the
comprehensive synthetic data and also
validating it which is great. And right
now you can also access the synthetic
data set through the CSC file that it
has generated.
Looks like Neo has finished the full
data set engineering and preparation
workflow. And it's truly amazing because
it analyzed the moderation categories.
It focused on creating the synthetic
data. It generated all the contents for
it. It also created the Python based
synthetic database generation framework
which is also great. And what's great is
that all the artifacts are now including
the CSV data set as well as the schema
JSON file where it's documenting the
validated uh data set which is great
because this way you can now access the
synthetic data that we had requested it
to generate for the next phase which is
training the baseline classification
model which is where it's working on
this next step. But personally, I'm
truly impressed as to how Neo was able
to handle the entire data set creation
process. It was able to do this fully
autonomously from defining the schema
and the annotation guidelines to
generate a fully validated highquality
synthetic data set. It not only ensured
the balanced coverage across all harmful
content categories, but it also
incorporated multilel support as well as
reproducibility which you can see within
the exploreration validation. It was
able to focus on this. It also
demonstrated how capable it was in terms
of managing complex end toend ML
workflows without manual intervention. I
didn't do anything. It did all of this
autonomously which is quite impressive.
So, looks like Neil was successfully
able to train the baseline models for
chat moderation with the logistic
regression classifier and achieved a
92.4 percentage on the F1 score and a
90% on recall. So now what it's going to
work on is having it build a
productionready real-time API using
flask and fast API and it's going to
work on loading the trained models as
well as providing the endpoints per
category for moderation outputs. So all
of this is done autonomously by Neo.
It's going to create a fully deployable
system ready to integrate into a live
chat environment. And you can see that
right now it is writing the code for all
of this to be functional all on its own
with the demo API as well with the
validation as well as the inference.
So looks like the chat moderation API
environment is ready for production and
what I've done now is I have approved it
myself as well with human in the loop
and I have now requested it to actually
focus on the next phase to deploy and
demonstrate the chat moderation
pipeline. This is where I told it to
actually execute this where I want to
access it to see how it actually works.
And all of this has now worked on the
documentation which you can see there's
multiple different files that it has
worked upon. It audited the trails the
responsibility checks as well as
ensuring the system is ready for
production grade features. It is now
ready to actually access after this next
step which is where we'll be demoing
this chat pipeline that we had created.
So it looks like it is fully complete
now. I have an API endpoint that's
actually running as well as the front
end that has been fully coded out and
you can see that it's now showcasing the
complete chat moderation pipeline. You
can see right now that it is showcasing
the messages that it has detected that
may be a part of the detection
categories that we have set that may
contain profanity, harassment, spam or
threats. The system status is running
right now which you can see with the API
status that is currently running. And
then you also have a good condensed
version of the analytics like the total
messages, flagged content, blocked
latency and such forth. You can even
export the contents that it has worked
upon. But you can see that it created
this fullon complete chat moderation
pipeline with the front end as well. But
the fact that it also created the
synthetic data was just impressive. This
data was fully developed on its own as
well as all of these lines of code in
that single sitting. If you like this
video and would love to support the
channel, you can consider donating to my
channel through the super thanks option
below. Or you can consider joining our
private Discord where you can access
multiple subscriptions to different AI
tools for free on a monthly basis, plus
daily AI news and exclusive content,
plus a lot more. But that's basically
how Neo was able to autonomously build
that complete chat moderation pipeline
for me. from building that high quality
synthetic data set to training baseline
models to also deploying a production
ready API and lastly enabling real-time
moderation. This isn't just a
demonstration of a random AI coder or
just a basic AI. It's a glimpse into
fully autonomous ML engineering that can
achieve streamlining complex workflows
and delivering production ready
solutions with minimal human
intervention. With Neo, tasks that used
to take weeks or months can now be
handled faster, smarter, and more
reliably. And it's going to empower ML
engineers to focus on insights and
strategy rather than repetitive
implementation. So, if you're looking to
get started, I'll leave a link to this
in the description below so that you can
easily sign up for the early access. And
I'll leave also all the other links like
the demos, the docs, and so much more.
But with that thought, guys, thank you
guys so much for watching. I hope you
enjoyed today's video. Make sure you
subscribe to the second channel, join
the newsletter, make sure you join our
private Discord, follow me on Twitter,
and lastly, make sure you guys
subscribe, turn on notification bell,
like this video, and please take a look
at our previous videos because there is
a lot of content that you'll truly
benefit from. But with that thought,
guys, have an amazing day. Spread
positivity, and I'll see you guys fairly
shortly. He suffers.